Architecture Slide Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Architecture Slide Collection
1960-2005
VRC 1000
Yale University Arts Library
83
498 boxes in 83 containers
Collection consists of color and black and white 35 mm slides of architecture, worldwide.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Collection consists of color and black and white 35 mm slides of architecture, worldwide.
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically by period style. Built structures further arranged by country, then by city or other location, and building type. Unbuilt structures arranged by architect or firm name.
Architecture; Slides; Reproductions
- Egypt (Transfer to the Babylonian Collection, 2008)
  - Denonm V.-D. Voyage..1802
  - Description de l'Egypte 1809-22
  - Known Sites
    - Abu Simbel
    - Abu Sir
    - Abydos
    - Dahshur
    - Deir El Bahari
    - Dendera
    - Edfu
    - Esna
    - Giza
      - Sphinx
      - Pyramids
    - Hierankonpolis
    - Karnak
      - Temple of Amon
        - Hypostyle Hall
      - Temple of Ptah
    - Kom Ombo
    - Luxor
    - Medinet Habu
    - Medum
    - Meroe
    - Philae
    - Sakkara
      - Pyramid Complex of Zoser
        - Step pyramid
    - Serabit el-Khadim
    - Tell-el-Amarna
    - Thebes
      - Valley of the Kings
- Near East (Transfer to the Babylonian Collection, 2008)
  - Ebla
  - Jerusalem
  - Ugarit
- Anatolia (Transfer to the Babylonian Collection, 2008)
  - Hittite
    - Boghaz-Koy
    - Karabel
    - Yazilikaya
- Mesopotamia (Transfer to the Babylonian Collection, 2008)
  - Sumerian
    - Ur
    - Warka
  - Babylonia
    - Babylon
  - Assyria
    - Tepe Gawra
- Persia (Transfer to the Babylonian Collection, 2008)
  - Belevi
  - Ctesiphon
  - Nacsh-I-Rustam
  - Persepolia
  - Taq-I-Bustan
- Phoenician (Transfer to the Babylonian Collection, 2008)
  - Various
- Aegean (Transfer to the Babylonian Collection, 2008)
  - Apesokari
  - Chrysolakkos
  - Chrysostomos
  - Enkomi
  - Gournia
  - Hagia Triada
  - Hagios Kyrillos
  - Kamilari
  - Karpophora
  - Khirokitia
  - Kition, Cyprus
  - Knossos
  - Komo, Crete
  - Lebena
  - Mallia
  - Mycenae
    - Lion Gate
    - Treasury of Atreus
  - Palaikastro
  - Phaestus
  - Platanos
  - Prinias
  - Prinirtiko Pyrcos
  - Pylos
  - Thera
  - Thulaka, Crete
  - Tiryns
  - Troezen
  - Troy
  - Tylissos
  - Vasiliki
- Greece (Transfer to the Babylonian Collection, 2008)
  - Beaux-Arts Reconstructions
  - Construction
  - Orders
  - Aegina
  - Agrigentum
    - Temple of Concord
    - Temple of the Dioscuri
    - Temple of Hera
    - Temple of Olympian Zeus
  - Alexandria
  - Argos
  - Arycanda
  - Aspendos
  - Athens
    - Acropolis
      - Agora
      - Erectheum
      - Kerameikos
      - Monument to Lysicrates
      - Parthenon
      - Propylaia
      - Stoa of Attalus
      - Temple of Athena Nike
      - Temple of Zeus
      - Theater of Dionysus
      - Theseum
      - Tower of the Wind
  - Bassae
  - Claros
  - Corfu
  - Corinth
  - Crimisa
  - Cumae
  - Daphni
  - Delos
  - Delphi
  - Eleusis
  - Epidaurus
  - Halicarnassus
  - Isthmia
  - Kastoria
  - Knidos
  - Kos
  - Kourion, Cyprus
  - Lindos
  - Magnesia on the Maeander
  - Mamurt-Kalen
  - Megalopolis
  - Messene
  - Miletus
  - Nemrud Dagh (Turkey)
  - Olympia
    - Temple of Hera
    - Temple of Zeus
  - Olynthus
  - Paestum
    - Temple of Athena
    - Temple of Hera I
    - Temple of Hera II
  - Paleapaphos, Cyprus
  - Pella
  - Perachora
  - Pergamon
    - Theater
  - Perge
  - Priene
  - Rodi
  - Salamis
  - Samos
  - Samothrace
  - Sardis
  - Segesta
  - Selinus
  - Sounion
  - Sparta
  - Syracuse
  - Tegea
  - Teos
  - Thermon
  - Troy
  - Vergina
- Italic (Transfer to the Babylonian Collection, 2008)
  - Various
- Etruscan (Transfer to the Babylonian Collection, 2008)
  - Bolsena
  - Casal Marittimo
  - Cerveteri
  - Chiusi
  - Civita Castellana
  - Falerii
  - Fiesole
  - Marzabotto
  - Norchia
  - Perugia
  - Pyrgi
  - Rome
  - Segni
  - Tarquinia
  - Veii
  - Volterra
- Roman (Transfer to the Babylonian Collection, 2008)
  - General
    - Architects
    - Beaux-Arts Reconstructions
    - Construction
    - Orders
    - Ornament
    - Roads
    - Vaulting
  - Known Sites
    - Aerea
    - Aezani
    - Agrigentum
    - Alatri
    - Alba Fucens
    - Albano
    - Alcantara
    - Amman
    - Ankara
    - Antioch
    - Aosta
    - Apames
    - Aphrodisias
    - Arles
    - Aspendos
    - Assisi
      - Temple of Minerva Medica
    - Athens
    - Autun
    - Baalbek
      - Main Courtyard
      - Temple of the Sun (Large)
      - Temple of Jupitor of Bacchus
        - Exterior
        - Interior
      - Circular Temple of Venus
    - Batae
    - Benevenuto
      - Arch of Trajan
    - Boscotrecase
    - Bosra
    - Brescia
    - Bulla Regia
    - Byblos
    - Caerwent
    - Caesarea
    - Capua
    - Carpentras
    - Carthage
    - Catania
    - Chedworth, Britain
    - Chollerford, Britain
    - Corbridge, Britain
    - Cordoba
    - Cori
    - Cosa
    - Damascus
    - Dana
    - Djebel-Oust
    - Djemila
    - Ephesus
      - Temple of Hadrian
    - Ferento
    - Gabii
    - Gerasa
      - Collonaded Street
      - Elliptical Forum
      - Nymphaeum
      - Temple of Artemis Great Propylon
      - Temple of Zeus
      - Triumphal Arch
    - Guadalajara
    - Hadrian's Wall
    - Herculaneum
      - Baths
      - Houses
    - Hierapolis
    - Isola Sacra
    - Italica
    - Jericho
    - Korykos
    - Langres
    - Latakia
    - Lepcis Magna
      - Arch of Septimus Severus
      - Baths
      - Harbor
      - Markets
      - Nymphaeum
      - Severan Basilica
      - Severan Forum
      - Theater
    - London
    - Mactaris
    - Medinocelli
    - Merida
    - Milan
    - Misenum
    - Naples
    - Niha
    - Nimes
      - Maison Carree
      - Temple of Diana
    - Nyssa
    - Oplontis
    - Orange
    - Orvieto
    - Ostia
      - Construction Detail
      - Baths
      - Houses
      - Markets
      - Streets
      - Tombs
      - Warehouses
    - Oudna
    - Palmyra
      - Colonnade
      - Temple of Bel
      - Tetrapylon
      - Theater
      - Triumphal Arch
    - Paris
    - Pergamon
      - Asklepion
      - Basilica
      - Temple of Dionysus
    - Petra
      - El Deir Tomb
      - Khamza
      - Palace Tomb
      - Rock Cut Tomb
    - Piazza Armerina
    - Pompeii
      - Basilica
      - Baths
      - Forum
      - Houses
        - House of the Faun
        - House of the Vettii
      - Streets
      - Temples
      - Theaters
    - Pont du Gard
    - Pozzuoli
    - Praeneste
      - Temple of Fortuna
    - Rheims
    - Rimini
    - Rome
      - Air View
      - Maps and Plans
      - Model
      - Aqueducts
      - Arches
        - Argentarii
        - Constaintine
          - Aurelian Panel
          - Constantinian Reliefs
          - Hadrianic Medallions
          - Trajanic Frieze
          - Arch of Janus Quadrifons
          - Septimus Severus
        - Arch of Titus
      - Basilicas
        - Constantine & Maxentius
        - Basilica Julia
        - Ulpia
      - Baths
        - Caracalla
        - Diocletian
      - Bridges
      - Circuses
      - Cloaca Maxima
      - Colosseum
        - Exterior
        - Interior
      - Columns
        - Marcus Aurelius
        - Column of Trajan
      - Forums
        - Augustus
        - Forum Romanum
        - Trajan
      - Gates
      - Houses
      - Markets
        - Trajan Market
      - Palaces
        - Domus Aurea
        - Domus Transitoria
      - Palatine Hill
        - Vestibule
        - Domus Augustana
        - Domus Flavia
        - Palace of Domitian
      - Pantheon
        - Exterior
        - Interior
          - Dome
      - Streets
      - Temples
        - Claudianum
        - Largo Argentina
        - Fortuna Virilis
        - Minerva
        - Temple of Romulus
        - Venus and Roma
        - Vesta
      - Theaters
      - Tombs
        - Tomb of Augustus
        - Hadrian's
        - Mausoleum of Tor de'Schiavi
      - Villas
      - Walls
      - Warehouses
    - Sabratha
    - S. Remy
    - S. Vito
    - Salonika
      - Arch of Galerius
    - Seeia
    - Segnia
    - Segovia
    - Sidon
    - Sorrento
    - Spalato
      - Palace of Diolcetian
    - Sufetula
    - Susa
    - Taormina
    - Tarragona
    - Terracina
    - Thenae
    - Thignica
    - Thuburbo Majus
    - Thugga
    - Thysdrus (El Djem)
    - Timgad
    - Tivoli
      - Temple of Vesta
      - Hadrian's Villa
        - Model
        - Baths
        - Canopus and Serapaeum
        - Maritime Theater
        - Piazza d'Oro
        - Poikile
    - Toledo
    - Trier
      - Basilica
      - Baths
      - Porta Nigra
    - Tripoli
    - Turin
    - Tyndaris
    - Utica
    - Verona
    - Vienne
    - Vindolanda (Britain)
    - Viroconium
    - Volubilis (Morocco)
    - Zaghouan
- Architecture – General (Box 1)
  General
  This section covered general architecture and planning examples not usefully located by date or place. [Slide boxes 1-6]
  - Various [Slide box 1] (Box 1)
  - Airports (Box 1)
  - Architectural Orders (Box 1)
  - Bridges (Box 1)
    - Various (Box 1)
    - Arch-type (Box 1)
      - Concrete (Box 1)
      - Metal (Box 1)
        - Coalbrookdale Bridge (Box 1)
    - Cantilever (Box 1)
    - Truss (Box 1)
    - Suspension (Box 1)
    - Covered bridges (Box 1)
  - Construction (Box 1)
  - Building types (Box 1)
  - Construction details (Box 1)
    - Vaults (Box 1)
  - Construction Failures (Box 1)
  - Construction Materials (Box 1)
    - Various (Box 1)
    - Adobe (Box 1)
    - Brick [Slide boxes 1-2] (Box 1)
    - Concrete [Slide box 2] (Box 1)
    - Wood (Box 1)
  - Construction Principles (Box 1)
  - Construction Types (Box 1)
    - Various (Box 1)
    - Arch-Rib (Box 1)
    - Cable (Box 1)
    - Cantilever (Box 1)
    - Concrete (Box 1)
      - Pre-Cast (Box 1)
    - Frame (Box 1)
      - Various (Box 1)
      - Balloon frame (Box 1)
    - Suspended (Box 1)
  - Fortifications [Slide boxes 2-3] (Box 1)
  - Gardens [Slide box 3] (Box 1)
  - Landscape (Box 1)
  - Lighting [Slide box 4] (Box 1)
    Xx for other examples of lighting see Industrial Design: Lighting fixtures; Furniture U.S. 19th-20th c. and for floodlighting see Arch. Renaissance Mexico
    — Mexico City—Cathedral; ---Mexico City---National Palace; Arch. Gothic France
    — Paris—Notre Dame; Arch. XIX-XX Denmark—Copenhagen—Tivoli Amusement Park; Sculpture Italy—Bernini—Fountain of 4 Rivers, Rome
  - Planning (Box 1)
    - Various (Box 1)
    - Air views (Box 1)
    - City plans [Slide boxes 4-5] (Box 1)
    - Types of plans [Slide boxes 5] (Box 1)
      - Allotment scheme (Box 1)
      - Attraction plan (Box 1)
      - Grid plan (Box 1)
      - Radial-Concentric plan (Box 1)
      - Site plan (Box 1)
      - Villeneuve plan (Box 1)
  - Hypothetical Cities (Box 1)
  - Population (Box 1)
  - Space models (Box 1)
  - Solar architecture (Box 1)
  - Vernacular architecture (Box 1)
- Early Medieval (Box 1)
  [Slide box 6]
  - Church Types (Box 1)
  - Construction (Box 1)
  - Monasteries (Box 1)
  - Known Sites (Box 1)
    - Aachen Aix-la-Chapelle (Box 1)
    - Imperial Palace (Box 1)
    - Palatine Chapel (Box 1)
    - AbuGosh, Palestine [Slide box 7] (Box 2)
    - Achtamar (Armenia) (Box 2)
    - Alahan Monastir (Box 2)
    - Albenga (Box 2)
    - Anagni (Box 2)
    - Angers (Box 2)
    - Ani (Box 2)
    - Apamea (Box 2)
    - Arta (Box 2)
    - Athens (Box 2)
    - Auxerre (Box 2)
    - Bagaran (Box 2)
    - Banos (Spain) (Box 2)
    - Bardolino (Box 2)
    - Barton-on-Humber (Box 2)
    - Benabil (Box 2)
    - Benevento (Box 2)
    - Bethany (Box 2)
    - Bethlehem (Box 2)
    - Bradford-on-Avon [Slide box 8] (Box 2)
    - Braga (Box 2)
    - Brescia (Box 2)
    - Brindisi (Box 2)
    - Brixworth (Box 2)
    - Burgos (Box 2)
    - Caeserea (Box 2)
    - Canosa (Box 2)
    - Canterbury (Box 2)
    - Capernaum (Box 2)
    - Cappadocia (Turkey) (Box 2)
    - Cassino (Box 2)
    - Centcelles (Spain) (Box 2)
    - Centula (Box 2)
    - Chios Island (Box 2)
    - Cividale Del Friuli (Box 2)
    - Cologne (Box 2)
    - Constantinople (Box 2)
      - General: plans [Slide boxes 8-9] (Box 2)
      - General: Views and Walls [Slide box 9] (Box 2)
        - Hippodrome (Box 2)
      - Churches (Box 2)
        - Constaintine Lips Church (Box 2)
        - Hagia Irene (Box 2)
        - Hagia Sophia (Box 2)
          - Exterior [Slide box 10] (Box 2)
          - Interior (Box 2)
          - Dome (Box 2)
          - Galleries (Box 2)
          - Horologian Gate (Box 2)
          - Narthex (Box 2)
          - Side Walls (Box 2)
          - Interior Details (Box 2)
            - Capitals [Slide box 11] (Box 2)
        - Kalenderhane Djami (Box 2)
        - Kariye Djami (Chora Church) (Box 2)
        - Myrelaion (Box 2)
        - S. John Studion (Box 2)
        - S. Mary Pammakarristos (Box 2)
        - S. Polyeuktos (Box 2)
        - Saviour/Christ Pantocrator [Slide boxes 11-12] (Box 2)
        - SS. Sergius & Bacchus [Slide box 12] (Box 2)
          - Exterior (Box 2)
          - Interior (Box 2)
        - S. Theodore (Box 2)
          - Exterior (Box 2)
          - Interior (Box 2)
      - Cisterns (Box 2)
      - Columns (Box 2)
      - Palaces (Box 2)
    - Corinth (Box 2)
    - Corvey [Slide box 13] (Box 3)
    - Crete (Box 3)
    - Cyprus (Box 3)
    - Dag Pazari (Turkey) (Box 3)
    - Damascus (Box 3)
    - Dana (Syria) (Box 3)
    - Daphni (Box 3)
    - Dar Kita (Syric) (Box 3)
    - Dau Pendeli Monastery (Greece) (Box 3)
    - Deerhurst (Box 3)
    - Dover (Box 3)
    - Earls Barton, England (Box 3)
    - Ephesus (Box 3)
    - Escomb (Box 3)
    - Etschmiadzin (Box 3)
    - Evrecy (Box 3)
    - Ezra (Box 3)
    - Farfa (Box 3)
    - Fulda [Slide box 14] (Box 3)
    - Gerasa (Box 3)
    - Germigny-des-Pres (Box 3)
    - Goltho (England) (Box 3)
    - Gracanica, Yugoslavia (Box 3)
    - Grandlieu (Box 3)
    - Grenoble (Box 3)
    - Halberstadt (Box 3)
    - Hexham (Box 3)
    - Hildesheim (Box 3)
    - Hippo (Box 3)
    - Hochst (Box 3)
    - Hosios Loukas (Box 3)
    - Il-Barah (Box 3)
    - Iona (Box 3)
    - Ireland [Slide boxes 14-15] (Box 3)
    - Jarrow [Slide box 15] (Box 3)
    - Jerusalem (Box 3)
      - Plans (Box 3)
        - Mosaic of Madaba (Box 3)
      - Churches (Box 3)
        - Holy Sepulchre (Box 3)
          - Plans (Box 3)
          - 4th c. Constantine basilica (Box 3)
          - 11th c. rebuilding (Box 3)
          - 12thc-20th c present (Box 3)
            - Exterior 12th– 20th century [Slide boxes 15-16] (Box 3)
            - Interior 12th -20th century [Slide box 16] (Box 3)
        - Temple of Herod (Box 3)
          - Gates (Box 3)
    - Jouarre (Box 3)
    - Jumieges (Box 3)
    - Kal'at Sim'an (Box 3)
      - S. Simeon Stylites (Box 3)
        - Exterior (Box 3)
        - Interior (Box 3)
    - Kalb Lauzeh (Box 3)
    - Kastoria (Greece) (Box 3)
    - Kheghard (Armenia) (Box 3)
    - Kornelimunster (Germany) (Box 3)
    - Lerins, France (Box 3)
    - Lithrankomi (Cyprus) (Box 3)
    - London (Box 3)
    - Lorsch (Box 3)
      - Gateway (Box 3)
      - Monastery (Box 3)
    - Malles (Box 3)
    - Marbaka (Greece) (Box 3)
    - Marseilles (Box 3)
    - Messina (Box 3)
    - Meteora (Box 3)
    - Milan [Slide box 17] (Box 3)
      - S. Lorenzo (Box 3)
    - Mistail, Switzerland (Box 3)
    - Mistra (Box 3)
      - Churches (Box 3)
        - Afentico (Box 3)
        - Metropolis (Box 3)
        - S. Theodore (Box 3)
    - Monkwearmouth (Box 3)
    - Mt. Athos [Slide box 18] (Box 3)
    - Mt. Sinai (Box 3)
    - Mt. Tabor (Box 3)
    - Mtskbeta (Box 3)
    - Naples (Box 3)
    - Nava (Spain) (Box 3)
    - Naxos (Box 3)
    - Nocera Superiore (Box 3)
    - North Elmham (Box 3)
    - Nouaille (Box 3)
    - Orense (Box 3)
    - Ostia (Box 3)
    - Otranto (Box 3)
    - Oviedo (Box 3)
    - Paderborn (Box 3)
    - Palencia (Box 3)
    - Parenzo (Box 3)
    - Patirion (Box 3)
    - Patmos (Box 3)
    - Pavia (Box 3)
    - Pergamom (Box 3)
    - Perugia (Box 3)
    - Philippi (Box 3)
    - Poitiers (Box 3)
    - Pomposa (Italy) (Box 3)
    - Qalb Loze (Box 3)
    - Quedlinburg (Box 3)
    - Ravenna (Box 3)
      - Churches (Box 3)
      - Bapistry of the Orthodox [Slide box 19] (Box 4)
      - S. Apollinare in Classe (Box 4)
      - S. Apollinare Nuovo (Box 4)
      - S. John the Evangelist (Box 4)
      - S. Michele in Africisco (Box 4)
      - S. Vitale (Box 4)
        - Tombs (Box 4)
          - Tomb of Galla Placida (Box 4)
          - Tomb of Theodoric [Slide boxes 19-20] (Box 4)
    - Reculver [Slide box 20] (Box 4)
    - Regensburg (Box 4)
    - Reichenau (Box 4)
    - Repton (Box 4)
    - Resafa (Box 4)
    - Ripon (Box 4)
    - Rome (Box 4)
      - Catacombs (Box 4)
      - Churches (Box 4)
        - S. Agnese (Box 4)
        - S. Clemente [Slide box 21] (Box 4)
        - S. Constanza (Box 4)
          - Exterior (Box 4)
          - Interior (Box 4)
        - S. Giovanni in Fonte (Box 4)
        - SS. Giovanni E Paolo (Box 4)
        - Giovanni Laterano (S. John) (Box 4)
        - S. Lorenzo f.l.m. (Box 4)
        - S. Maria Antiqua (Box 4)
        - S. Maria in Cosmedin (Box 4)
          - Exterior (Box 4)
          - Interior (Box 4)
        - S. Maria Maggiore (Box 4)
        - S. Maria in Trastevere (Box 4)
        - S. Martino Al Monti [Slide box 22] (Box 4)
        - S. Paolo f.l.m. (Box 4)
        - Old S. Peter's (Box 4)
          - Plans (Box 4)
          - Sections (Box 4)
          - Exterior (Box 4)
          - Interior (Box 4)
          - Cemetery (Box 4)
        - S. Prassede (Box 4)
        - SS. Quattro Coronati (Box 4)
        - S. Sabina [Slide box 23] (Box 4)
        - S. Stefano Rotondo (Box 4)
          - Palaces (Box 4)
    - Ruweha (Syria) (Box 4)
    - S. Comba de Bande (Box 4)
    - S. Gall (Box 4)
      - Models (Box 4)
      - Original Plan of c. 820 (Box 4)
      - Plans Redrawn, Interpreted (Box 4)
      - Reconstruction Drawings (Box 4)
    - Salonika (Box 4)
      - Hagia Sophia (Box 4)
      - Holy Apostles (Box 4)
      - S. Demetrius (Box 4)
      - Church of S. George (Box 4)
    - San Miguel de Escalada (Spain) (Box 4)
    - Sardis (Box 4)
    - Sebaste (Box 4)
    - Seelingenstadt (Box 4)
    - Skellig Michael (Box 4)
    - Skripou (Box 4)
    - Soissons (Box 4)
    - Stoughton (Box 4)
    - Sufetula (Box 4)
    - Tarrasa (Box 4)
    - Toledo (Box 4)
    - Torcello (Box 4)
      - Cathedral (Box 4)
    - Tourmain (Box 4)
    - Tours (Box 4)
    - Trier (Box 4)
    - Tuscania (Box 4)
    - Valdedios (Box 4)
    - Venice (Box 4)
      - Pillars of Acre (Box 4)
      - S. Marco (Box 4)
        - Exterior (Box 4)
          - Façade [Slide box 24-25] (Box 4)
            - Façade: Center Door [Slide box 25] (Box 5)
            - Façade: Side Doors (Box 5)
            - Façade: Gables (Box 5)
            - Center Gable with Bronze Horses (Box 5)
          - South Side (Box 5)
          - Treasury Wall (Box 5)
        - Interior (Box 5)
          - Atrium (Box 5)
          - Ciborium (Box 5)
          - Domes & Cupolas (Box 5)
          - Pulpit & Iconostasis [Slide box 26] (Box 5)
    - Vienne (Box 5)
    - Vreden (Box 5)
    - Whitby (Box 5)
    - Winchester (Box 5)
    - Wing (Box 5)
    - Yeavering (Box 5)
    - Zadar (Box 5)
    - Zamora (Box 5)
- Romanesque (Box 5)
  - General (Box 5)
  - Plans and Sections (Box 5)
  - Vaulting (Box 5)
- Britain (Box 5)
  - General (Box 5)
  - Known sites (Box 5)
    - Various (Box 5)
    - Barfreston (Box 5)
    - Bosham (Box 5)
    - Cambridge (Box 5)
    - Canterbury (Box 5)
    - Cashel, Ireland (Box 5)
    - Castle Acre (Box 5)
    - Castle Rising (Box 5)
    - Castor (Box 5)
    - Clonfert (Box 5)
    - Colchester (Box 5)
    - Durham (Box 5)
      - Various (Box 5)
      - Churches (Box 5)
        - Cathedral (Box 5)
          - Plans and Sections (Box 5)
          - Exterior (Box 5)
            - Various [Slide boxes 26-27] (Box 5)
            - Cloister [Slide box 27] (Box 5)
          - Interior (Box 5)
            - Various (Box 5)
            - Nave (Box 5)
            - Choir (Box 5)
            - Transept (Box 5)
            - Galilee Chapel (Box 5)
    - Hedingham (Box 5)
    - Hereford (Box 5)
    - Kilpec (Box 5)
    - Leominster (Box 5)
    - Lincoln (Box 5)
      - Various (Box 5)
      - Churches (Box 5)
        Xx for Lincoln Cathedral see Architecture Gothic
    - London (Box 5)
      - Tower of London (Box 5)
    - Ludlow Castle (Box 5)
    - Malmesbury (Box 5)
    - Melbourne, Derbyshire (Box 5)
    - Melrose Abbey [Slide box 28] (Box 5)
    - Nether Cerne, Dorset (Box 5)
    - Northampton (Box 5)
    - Norwich (Box 5)
    - Oakham Castle, Rutland (Box 5)
    - Old Sarum (Box 5)
    - Pevensey (Box 5)
    - Rochester (Box 5)
    - St. Albans (Box 5)
    - Southwell (Box 5)
    - Tewkesbury (Box 5)
    - Urquhart Castle, Scotland (Box 5)
    - Wales (Box 5)
    - Waltham (Box 5)
    - Winchester (Box 5)
- Flanders (Box 5)
  - Various (Box 5)
- France (Box 5)
  - General (Box 5)
  - Cities (Box 5)
    - Various (Box 5)
    - Agde (Box 5)
    - Angouleme (Box 5)
      - Various (Box 5)
      - S. Pierre (Box 5)
        - Various (Box 5)
        - Exterior (Box 5)
          - Various (Box 5)
          - Sculpture (Box 5)
        - Interior (Box 5)
    - Anzy-Le-Duc (Box 5)
    - Arles [Slide box 29] (Box 5)
      - Various (Box 5)
      - S. Trophime (Box 5)
    - Aulnay (Box 5)
      - S. Pierre (Box 5)
    - Autun (Box 5)
      - Various (Box 5)
      - S. Lazare (Box 5)
        - Exterior (Box 5)
        - Interior (Box 5)
    - Avallon (Box 5)
      - S. Lazare (Box 5)
    - Avignon (Box 5)
    - Baume-Les-Messieurs [Slide box 30] (Box 5)
    - Bayeux (Box 5)
    - Beaulieu-Les-Loches (Box 5)
    - Beaulieu-sur-Dordogne (Box 5)
    - Bernay (Box 5)
    - Berze-La-Ville (Box 5)
    - Bourges (Box 5)
    - Brioude (Box 5)
    - Caen (Box 5)
      - La Trinite (Box 5)
        - Various (Box 5)
        - Exterior (Box 5)
        - Interior (Box 5)
      - S. Etienne (Box 5)
        - Various (Box 5)
        - Exterior (Box 5)
        - Interior (Box 5)
    - Cahors (Box 5)
    - Carennac (Box 5)
    - Chapaize (Box 5)
    - Charlieu (Box 5)
    - Charroux (Box 5)
    - Chartres (Box 5)
    - Chauriat (Box 5)
    - Chauvigny (Box 5)
    - Clunny [Slide box 31] (Box 6)
      - Churches (Box 6)
        - Various (Box 6)
        - Abbey (Box 6)
          - Various (Box 6)
          - Plans, Sections & Models (Box 6)
          - Reconstruction/Restoration (Box 6)
          - Engravings, Drawings, etc. (Box 6)
          - Abbey Church III, Exterior & Interior (Box 6)
    - Conques (Box 6)
      - Church of S. Foy (Box 6)
        - Various (Box 6)
        - Exterior (Box 6)
          - Various (Box 6)
          - Tympanum (Box 6)
        - Interior (Box 6)
          - Various [Slide boxes 31-32] (Box 6)
    - Corbeil [Slide box 32] (Box 6)
      Xx for slides of figures from Corbeil Portals, now in Louvre, see Sculpture France XII Century.
    - Dijon (Box 6)
      - S. Benigne (Box 6)
    - Donzy-Le-Pre (Box 6)
    - Fontenay (Box 6)
      - Abbey (Box 6)
        - Plans (Box 6)
        - Exterior (Box 6)
        - Chapter House (Box 6)
        - Church (Box 6)
        - Cloister (Box 6)
        - Forge (Box 6)
    - Fontevrault (Box 6)
    - Gigny (Box 6)
    - Gisors (Box 6)
    - Issoire (Box 6)
      - S. Pol or S. Austremoine (Box 6)
    - Jumiges (Box 6)
      - Abbey (Box 6)
    - La Charite Sur Loire [Slide box 33] (Box 6)
    - Langres (Box 6)
      - S. Amatre (Box 6)
      - S. Didier (Box 6)
      - S. Mammes (Box 6)
        - Exterior (Box 6)
        - Interior (Box 6)
    - Lavoute-Chilhac (Box 6)
    - Le Puy en Velay (Box 6)
      - Cathedral Notre Dame (Box 6)
      - S. Michel D'Aiguilhe (Box 6)
    - Lessay (Box 6)
    - Le Thoronet (Box 6)
    - Macon (Box 6)
    - Mauguelonne (Box 6)